why am i on the street
我为何会在街道上
Ji Tong appears
吉童出现了
Catch Ji Tong quickly
快抓住吉童
Ji Tong?
吉童？
What's going on
怎么回事
What's going on with this sound?
这声音是怎么回事
Is there something wrong with my ears?
是我的耳朵出问题了吗
What's going on
怎么回事
Why are you the way you are?
为何是你的样子
why your voice
为何是你的声音
How could I become you
我怎么会变成你
What the hell is going on
这到底是怎么回事
How long do I have to wait?
我还要等多久才行
Why don't you wake up? Why is this not a dream?
怎么一直不醒  这为何不是梦
Why on earth…
到底为什么…
How could I be in the body of an official?
我怎么会在从事官的身体里
Go back to where you came from
回去原本的地方吧
I want to go back to my own place
我要回去我自己那里
But...where is this
可是…这是哪里
Please tell the Empress of the Middle Temple
请转告中殿娘娘
It's an urgent matter related to my marriage
是与我婚事相关的急事
Yes
是
Could you please give me some advice?
方便请教一下吗
Meet again
又见面了
listen to her
听她这样说
It must be a woman I know
应该是认识的女人吧
Fortunately...nice to meet you?
幸…幸会？
This time you remember me
这次你记得我了
Didn't you recognize it last time?
上一次没认出来？
Of course I remember
我当然记得
I lost my way for a moment
我一时迷了路
May I ask where this is?
请问这里是何处
This is naturally the palace
这里自然是宫里
Ah...in the palace?
啊…宫里？
Yes, Miyazato
是啊  宫里
In the palace? Is this in the palace?
宫里吗  这是在宫廷中吗
The palace where the king lives?
君王居住的宫廷？
Why is it in the palace?
为何偏偏是宫里
I’m not familiar with this place, and I don’t know where the exit is.
人生地不熟  也不知道出口在哪里
You just said you knew me
你方才说认识我
So can you do me a favor?
那你能帮我一个忙吗
Good
好
Of course I would be happy to receive your help last time...
上次承蒙你的帮助  我当然乐意…
thank you
谢谢你
Where is the next door?
下一道门在哪里
Over there is Xieshengmen
那边是协生门
Sorry, could you please hurry up?
不好意思  麻烦你加快脚步
I'm in a hurry
我赶时间
OK
好的
Really like two restless ponies
真像两匹躁动的小马
But so strange
不过好奇怪
Why does that man look more and more like my son?
那个男的怎么越看越像我儿子
The slave is frightened
奴婢惶恐
Invite Judge Xu to come over
传徐判官过来
Thanks to you, I was able to come out smoothly
多亏有你  我才能顺利出来
Then you can let go now
那现在可以放手了吧
I was impatient. I'm sorry.
我一时心急  失礼了
Why are you entering the palace so late?
你这么晚了还入宫
It seems something big happened in the Robbery Bureau
看来捕盗厅出了大事
I think so
我想是的
I'll just go by myself next time
接下来我自己走就好
Thank you very much today
今日多谢了
Hailin
海林
My name is Hailin
我叫海林
It's the Shen family...
是慎家人…
My brother is the promotion officer of Huimin Department
兄长是惠民署的提调大人
Are you the sister of Mr. Ti Tiao?
你是提调大人的妹妹？
You look nothing alike
你们长得一点也不像
you are beautiful
你很美
I'll take my leave first
我先告辞了
See you next time
下次见面
hope you can remember my name
希望你能记得我的名字
why are you here
你怎么来了
Did you get the news so quickly?
你这么快就收到消息了吗
No
不是的
what
什么
I mean... I happened to be around here on business.
我的意思是…我正好有事来这附近
That's what I threw into the well
那是我丢进井里的
Found it so quickly
这么快就找到了啊
That's Ji Tong's thing
那是吉童的东西
Tonight, I will give you a lecture
今晚大司谏大人
Killed by Ji Tong
被吉童杀害了
Really?
是吗
two hours ago
两个时辰前
He sneaked into Da Sijian's mansion and escaped
他潜入大司谏府邸后逃走
It seems that he was injured near here.
似乎是在这附近受了伤
Did you shed so much blood?
流了这么多血吗
Difficulty moving due to injury
由于受伤后难以行动
So I abandoned the Baiding mask and the Yako
于是弃下白丁面具与矢箙
He changed back to his original appearance and ran away.
换回本来的面貌逃走了
He must have been unconscious for a long time
应该昏迷了很久才对
Have you woken up?
是醒来了吗
Someone still took me away
还是有人把我带走
Jiang is an official. Listen carefully.
姜从事官  你听好了
Ji Tong was framed
吉童是被栽赃的
Framed?
栽赃？
Think about it
你回想一下
last winter
在去年冬天
Those gangsters from Yuncong Street were caught stealing silk
云从街的那些地痞偷了丝绸被抓
Then they lied that Ji Tong stole it and gave it to them.
便谎称是吉童偷来送给他们的
I remember
我记得
People from the business group recognized one of the gangsters
商团的人认出其中一名地痞
Ji Tong was cleared of charges
吉童才洗清了罪名
More than that
何止如此
Rumors also say that Ji Tong is a criminal who kidnapped the bride.
传言还说吉童是抢亲的犯人
Abducted the daughter-in-law of Da Si Xian Mansion
掳走了大司宪府的儿媳
Later it was found out that she was the daughter-in-law of Da Si Xianfu
后来查出是大司宪府的儿媳
Eloped with the teacher
与教书先生私奔了
Is there anyone else using Ji Tong’s name?
又有人冒用吉童的名号吗
Unexpectedly, he even used Ji Dong's name to kill people.
没想到连杀人都冒用吉童的名号
In short
总之
You just need to follow the evidence and investigate
你只须追着证据调查
Don't be led away by fake blood letters
别被假的血书牵着走
obey
遵命
Those old cases just mentioned
方才提及的那些旧案
I never reported to you
我从未向你报告
How do you know the details and even the blood letter?
你怎会知道详情  甚至还知道血书
I think I heard it on the road.
好像是在路上听来的吧
Is that so?
是这样吗
Is there anyone found unconscious nearby?
附近可有发现晕倒在地的人
No
没有
But…
不过…
did you drink
你喝酒了吗
Probably
大概是吧
I heard that Dr. Hong’s wedding is today
听说洪医女的婚礼就在今日
Is it because of this?
是因为此事吗
I'm leaving
我要走了
where are you going
你要去哪
We’ll talk about it later. Wait a minute.
之后再说　　等等
Without Judge Xu accompanying me...
没有徐判官同行…
Your Majesty
大君大人
It turns out to be here
原来在这里
It seems that even the doctor has been here
看来连医员都来过了
Who brought me back?
是谁把我带回来的啊
Only we know about this, don't let any rumors leak about it
这件事就只有我们知道  别走漏风声
If word got out that the bride fainted outside her home
如果新娘在家外晕倒的事被传出去
It will only make the boss even more unhappy
只会让上头更不高兴
Okay, got it
好啦  知道了
Fortunately, I was discovered by the proprietress.
幸好是被东主婶发现
I don't know what she is doing there
都不知道她在那里做什么
Anyway, her husband is dead, so is she planning to run away?
反正丈夫也死了  所以她打算逃跑吗
Shut up
你给我闭嘴
Hello…
喂…
Wake up
醒醒啊
Why don't you wake up?
怎么不醒啊
My heart is still beating
心脏还在跳啊
Is there anyone inside?
里面有人吗
Could it be an empty shell?
该不会是空壳吧？
Is anyone here?
有人在吗
Is anyone home?
有没有人在家啊
What?
什么啊
Have you changed it back?
换回来了吗
Sure enough, I was just dreaming
果然只是在发梦
If it really comes back
若真的换回来了
Will it still look like this face?
看起来还会是这张脸吗
who are you?
你是谁？
The person who is speaking now
现在在说话的人
Is he the owner of this face?
是这张脸的主人吗
Are you the ancestor of the Hong family?
你是洪家恩祖吗
What the hell is going on
这到底是怎么回事
Have we really exchanged souls?
我们真的灵魂交换了吗
Is this reasonable?…
这合理吗…
Does your head hurt?
头很痛吗
How did the head hurt?
头是怎么受伤的
The road was too dark at night and I fell heavily when I went out.
夜路太黑  出门时摔了一大跤
how did you get here
你是怎么来到这里的
As soon as I opened my eyes, I fell down again
我一睁开眼就又倒下了
Before that, Da Si Jian’s servants had been here.
在那之前大司谏的奴婢有来过
It seems that he doesn't know that I am Ji Dong
看来他应该不知道我就是吉童
Wow…
哗…
I can actually be so unfamiliar with my face
我居然可以对我的脸陌生到这种程度
each other
彼此彼此
Let’s find a way to change it back first.
先找出换回来的办法吧
We need to get out of here first
我们要先离开这里
Are you able to walk?
你有办法走路吗
It's dawn
天亮了
Go back and take a nap
回去小睡一会吧
Father is coming out soon
父亲也快出来了
The little one has delivered the dinner as you asked.
小的已照你吩咐  把晚餐送过去了
Let her eat enough so she can sleep well
让她吃饱  能睡个好眠
Yes, the younger one retreated first.
是  小的先退下了
Looking downcast
一脸垂头丧气样
If this continues, something will happen to my family's ancestors as well.
再这样下去  连我家恩祖都要出事了
It would be better to just die
干脆死了还比较好
If you disappear without a sound
如果一声不响地消失
I'm afraid it will cause a commotion
恐怕会造成骚动
Tell the maid of this household
跟这户人家的男佣说
You have to go back to your parents’ house
你要回娘家一趟
Mother’s family?
娘家？
So where is this place?
那这里是哪里啊
Is it your in-laws?
难道是你的婆家吗？
Abominable
可恶
Why did you change to this place?
偏偏换到这种地方
This is my home since yesterday
从昨天起  这里就是我家了
Having said that
话说回来
Why do you help me change into mourning clothes?
为什么帮我换上丧服啊
Has anyone died in this family?
这户人家有人去世了吗
Ah that...
啊  那个…
What about this...
这个呢…
Someone is coming
有人来了
If you continue here, you will be discovered. I will hide first.
继续在这里会被发现  我先躲起来
Damn it, why is it that guy?
可恶  怎么偏偏是那家伙啊
What are you doing here so early in the morning?
一大清早  你来做什么
Wrong
不对
why did you come here
你怎么会来这里
I'll collect the body
我来收尸
It seems I came too early
看来我来得太早了
It’s over. How could he be the second young master of this family?
完蛋了  怎么会是这家的二少爷
Corpse?
尸体？
Why do you come here to find corpses...ah?
为什么要来这里找尸体…啊？
Aren't corpses usually placed behind the incense table?
通常尸体不是都放在香案后面吗
Why don't you go to the sarangcha to find...?
你怎么不去舍廊找…啊？
are you kidding me now
你现在是在开玩笑吗
No...
才没有…呢
It seems you have come to the wrong place
看来你是来错地方了
Hurry over there...
赶快过去…吧
It almost turned me off
差点就让我扫兴了
What should I do if I die before I get trampled?
如果还没被践踏就先死了  该怎么办
Hello
喂
What about me?
我呢
I don’t quite understand the context of this conversation right now.
现在不太能理解这个对话的脉络
Is this what a husband who just married his wife should say?
这是刚娶妻的丈夫该说的话吗
Husband?
丈夫？
what to do
怎么办
The newlyweds were so inseparable that it was too late
新婚夫妻如胶似漆都来不及了
What about trampling?
还说什么践踏？
It seems that there was a dispute between the couple last night.
看来昨晚夫妻间经历了一番争执啊
who is your husband
谁是你丈夫啊
Who else could it be?
还会是谁
You standing in front of me
站在我面前的你啊
I'm going crazy, really
我要疯了  真是的
Your joke has gone a bit too far since just now
你的玩笑从刚才就有点过火了
How does this look like a joke?
哪里像玩笑话了
are you crazy
你疯了吗
The husband you mentioned passed away last night
你说的那位丈夫昨晚已经去世了
How could he die?
怎么会死了？
If this mourning dress was worn because the husband died,
如果这身丧服是因为丈夫死了才穿的话
Then who are you?
那你又是谁？
answer
回答
grandson of the deceased
去世那位的孙子
Grandson?
孙子？
It's so late. Why are you here?
这么晚了  你为何来此？
Just think that I'm here to discipline the family. How about
就当我是来管教家眷的  如何
So that’s when…
所以那个时候才…
wait a moment
等一下
Since he already has grandchildren
既然他都已经有孙子了
My husband must be at least sixty or seventy years old.
我那位丈夫至少也超过六七十岁了吧
Is this marriage reasonable?
这桩婚事合理吗
you are really crazy
你是真的疯了
Still awake now
还是现在才清醒
I want to…
我想…
It should be the latter...right?
应该是后者…吧？
I think I should have been hit hard
我想我应该是受到巨大打击
will temporarily lose consciousness
才会暂时神智不清
Thanks to you, I was able to figure out the situation, Mr. Sun Tzu.
多亏你  我才能搞清楚状况  孙子大人
Also
还有
I just mistook you for my husband.
刚才把你误认成我丈夫的事
hope you can never forget
希望你能永远忘记
Even if you only have that thought for a moment
就算只有一瞬间有那种想法
It all makes me feel extremely humiliated
都让我觉得是莫大羞辱
It seems you are back to normal
看来你已经恢复正常了
But what about this attitude?
但这态度又是怎么回事
young master
少爷
All of you on the list came to express your condolences.
与你同榜诸位前来吊唁了
Go quickly
快去吧
The mourner cannot leave the party for too long...
丧主可不能离席太久…呢
Stop
你站住
Are you feeling well?
身子还好吗
Do you still remember that you were carried back last night?
你还记得自己昨晚是被人背回来的吗
Probably remember
大概记得
Anyway, this woman's body
反正这副女人之身
There is no need to come forward to receive condolences
也不必出面接待吊唁者
Don't let anyone in or out during the funeral.
治丧期间别让任何人进出此处
I'm going back to my parents' house
我回娘家一趟
Just pretend you don't know
你就当不知情
yes
是的
Hong Eun-jo, come out
洪恩祖  出来吧
Leave over the wall
翻墙离开
I don't want to stay in this home for a second
我一刻都不想再留在这个家
Where are you going?
你要走到哪里？
No one will pass this path
这条小径不会有人经过
Just say it here
就在此处说吧
The marriage is just like what you just heard
婚事就如同你刚才听到的
That gentleman is my nominal husband
那位老爷是我名义上的丈夫
They passed away as soon as they got married last night
昨晚一成亲便撒手人寰
Maybe you think this is unreasonable
或许你会觉得此事不可理喻
But it's common for people like me
但对我这种身份的人来说很常见
Sorry, I lied to you and said that the second young master of that family was my husband.
抱歉  我骗你说那家的二少爷是我丈夫
I thought it would be good for both of us to say that.
我以为那样说对彼此都好
This way you can give up sooner
这样你也能早点死心
I'll have less trouble
我也少点麻烦
Why haven't you said a word since just now?
从刚才开始你怎么就一言不发？
You have to say something to solve the situation at hand.
总要说点什么才能解决眼前的事态吧
Because I don't know what to say
因为我不知道该说些什么
I kept thinking along the way
一路上我不停思考
But can't say a word
却说不出半句话
I'm nothing to you
对你来说  我什么都不是
Not qualified to vent this anger
没资格发泄这股怒意
This may be a choice you made under difficulty
这或许是你艰难之下做出的选择
I can't blame easily
我也无法轻易责怪
But I don’t want to pretend to understand what you said, “This kind of marriage is very common.”
但也不想假装理解你说的「这种婚事很常见」
and absurdly agree with
并荒谬地赞同
What makes me most angry now is
现在让我最气愤的是
Because I'm not in my body
因为我不在自己的身体里
Even if I have to drag you out of that damn place,
就连要胡乱把你从那个鬼地方拖出来
Can't do it
都做不到
So we have to change our bodies back first.
所以我们要先把身体换回来才行
I can understand it as waiting for the change to come back
我可以理解成  等换回来之后
Will you carry out what you just said?
你就会履行方才所说的话吗
you understand very correctly
你理解得非常正确
I'm even thinking
我甚至在思考
How to destroy the family that facilitated this marriage?
要怎样毁掉促成这场婚事的家族
Only then can I vent my anger
才得已泄愤
What I'm most angry about is
我最生气的是
Don't know anything about this
对此事全然不知
And stupidly praying for you
还傻傻地替你祈福
Being stupid enough to put embroidered shoes into your hands
蠢到将绣花鞋塞到你手中的自己
So I’ll say the ugly things first.
所以我丑话先说在前头
I will be even more ruthless next time
接下来我会更加不留情
Not even a moment's hesitation
半刻都不会犹疑
Let’s end this topic here.
这个话题就到此为止吧
You didn't have to get married
你原本可以不成亲的
You can also tell me
也可以跟我说啊
I don't think I need to give up on the marriage
我不觉得需要作罢婚事
Not so pitiful that he needs help from others
也没有可怜到需要他人帮助
Although people who are bedridden
虽然卧病在床的人
It is deeply regrettable to die on the wedding day
在成亲当天去世让人深感遗憾
But I want to say that at least I can be in that home from now on
但我想说  至少从此能在那个家
Live without worries
衣食无忧地过活
Until we suddenly switch bodies
直到我们突然互换身体之前
So the first priority is to return to our respective bodies first.
所以当务之急是先回到各自的身体吧
You continue to enjoy your life while I go and do whatever I want
你继续享福  我则去任意胡闹
If we want to successfully implement each other's goals, let's do this
若想顺利执行彼此的目标就要这样做吧
Just treat it as a temporary consensus.
就当作暂时达成共识吧
Mom, are you okay?
娘  你没事吧
If the great master passes away
大老爷大人过世的话
What should our Eunjo do?
我们恩祖该怎么办
She became a widow at a young age
年纪轻轻就守寡啦
Can't you take her back?
不能把她接回来吗
She is married
她已经出嫁了
Now he belongs to that family
现在是那家的人了
Even if I die, I will die in that home. What can I do?
就算死也要死在那个家  能有什么办法
Unless she wants to run far away
除非她要逃得远远的
Run away?
逃跑吗
This is something I've never seen in a book
这是我在书中都没看过的事
Not to mention legends or folktales
更别说传说或民间故事了
No matter how you think about it, this doesn't look like something humans do.
再怎么想  这都不像人类所为
Do you mean God did it?
你的意思是老天爷做的吗
That's divine punishment, right?
那就是天谴吧？
At least I'm sure it's definitely not a blessing
至少可以确定绝对不是祝福
I won't be angry
我不会生气的
You really tell me the truth
你真的老实告诉我
Have you done nothing wrong recently?
你最近没做错什么事吗
No
没有
Even if I did something wrong
就算我做错什么
Why do you have to be punished with me?
为何你要跟我一起受罚？
The point is, why is it you and me?
重点在于  为何偏偏是你和我
When is your birthday?
你的生辰八字是何时？
Bingwu year Gengzi month Guihai day
丙午年  庚子月  癸亥日
It’s different from my sun pillar.
跟我的日柱不同啊
If you want to think in a superstitious direction, then be thorough.
既然要往迷信的方向想  那就彻底一点吧
follow me
跟我来
You are a medical woman. Don’t you have a medical explanation?
你是医女  没有医学上的解释吗
Be quiet
安静点
It will be taboo
会犯忌讳的
There's a virgin ghost living inside you
你身体内住了个处女鬼
can you see me
你看得见我吗
Can you really see anything?
你真的看得到什么吗
So you are a grown man
所以说你一个大男人
He understands women’s hearts better than women, right?
才比女人还懂女人心吧
This guy…
这家伙…
He's a playboy, right?
是花花公子吧
Get up
起身吧
Let’s do a ritual
做一场法事吧
I can help you exorcise ghosts
我可以帮你驱鬼
Hello
喂
I'm not trying to kick this woman out of my body
我并不打算把这个女人赶出我的身体
Do you want to try doing some rituals?
要不要试一试做法事
As long as the soul leaves the body
只要灵魂离开身体
At least try other methods
至少就能尝试其他办法吧
What if I never come back?
如果永远回不来呢
Are you planning to go for a walk in Huangquan?
是打算去黄泉散步吗
Could it be that it's not a soul exchange?
会不会并非是灵魂互换
But body swap?
而是身体互换？
So we should start with the body, right?
那应该从身体下手吧？
sincerely
真心诚意
hold religiously
虔诚地握住
Do you feel it?
有感觉吗
Not at all
完全没有
Didn’t you say you need to use your body?
你不是说要用身体吗
How can anything change if you just move your hands?
只动动手  哪会有什么改变？
Otherwise, what should I do?
不然要怎么办
Are you sure you have no selfish motives?
你确定没有私心吗
What selfishness?
什么私心？
(I don’t know when they started looking at the same place)
(不知从何时起  彼此看着同样地方)
Show some sincerity too
你也展现点诚意吧
what
什么
Good
好
(Even if you want to hide it, it will still gradually expand)
(即使想隐藏  依旧渐渐扩大)
(Want to hug you Loving you)
(想拥抱你  Loving you)
(I don’t want to let go for a moment)
(一刻都不想放开)
(Every day is filled with us)
(被我们填满的每一天)
(all seem to shine beautifully)
(似乎都美丽地闪耀着)
Did you feel anything?
有感觉到什么吗
Yes very loud
有  很大声
Is my heartbeat so loud?
我的心跳声有这么大声吗
are you kidding
你在开玩笑吗
Very pleasant
挺悦耳的
After the change comes back, you can listen to it as much as you want
等换回来之后  你再尽情听
I don’t think I’m exchanging my body for it.
我看也不是用身体来交换
When did we exchange?
我们是何时交换的？
Last night when people decided?
昨晚人定之时？
Will it be replaced by then?
到那时就会换回来了？
Is it all just a nightmare one night?
一切只是一晚的恶梦吗
It's time for people to decide
已到人定之时
nightmare…
恶梦…
It seems to have become longer
好像变长了
Abominable
可恶
You just said it doesn't seem to be man-made, right?
你刚才说这似乎不是人为的对吧
Then it’s useless no matter how hard one tries
那么人再怎么努力都没用
Doesn't it matter if we continue to live like this?
难道继续这样活下去也无所谓吗
I don’t even know when I will switch back
甚至不知道何时会换回来
So you are here
原来你在这里
There's a lot of commotion happening at your place
你的住处正闹得鸡飞狗跳
It's you again
又是你
Then I won’t say much more
那我就不多说了
You've already finished scolding with your expressions
你早就用表情骂完了
what
什么
Anyone who looks at it can tell that it was me who was dragged out
任谁看都知道是我被拖出来
why do you look like you want to blame me
为什么你看起来想责怪我
If you want to scold me, I'll scold this guy who won't let me go.
要骂也是骂不放我走的这家伙
"This guy"?
「这家伙」？
You always have to think about whose mouth this is, right?
你总要想想这张嘴是谁的吧
As long as it's right, it doesn't matter which mouth you say it from.
只要是对的  从哪张嘴说出都无妨吧
I said...
我说…
Ignore him and talk to me
你别理他  和我谈吧
What? No, I’m asking you to speak out.
什么　　不是  是叫你说出来
Yes
是
There's a lot of commotion in the palace right now
宫里现在闹得鸡飞狗跳
why
为什么
The Concubine orders you to enter the palace immediately
大妃娘娘命令你即刻入宫
Why is the empress like this?
大妃娘娘为何如此
Convey to empress
转达给娘娘
Now I am unable to enter the palace due to circumstances that do not allow it.
现在因为状况不允许  无法入宫
Now is not the time for you to speak
现在不是你能说话的时候
He only listens to your orders. Tell him.
他只听你的命令  你告诉他
"You"?
「你」？
The empress has even been on a hunger strike since last night
娘娘甚至从昨晚绝食至今
Say you won't eat anything until you come
说在你到来前什么都不吃
Because of me?
因为我？
Otherwise, who would it be because of?
不然会是因为谁呢
What kind of trouble did this body cause?
这副身躯究竟闯下了什么祸
No dignity or character at all
毫无威严及品格可言
He doesn't even have the status to speak
连讲话都没有名分
It happened that I revealed my identity in this body
偏偏是我在这副身躯时说出身分
You first go and report to the Maharaja that your Majesty will enter the palace.
你先去禀告大君大人会入宫
I said
我说
It seems you are going to go there
看来你要去一趟了
Your Majesty
大君大人
Your Majesty... Your Majesty?
大君…大人？
Yes, it's you
对  就是你
Your Majesty
大君大人
So
所以说
Are you the second son of His Royal Highness?
你是先王殿下的二儿子？
Yes
对
Is he also the younger brother of the current Lord?
也是现任主上殿下的弟弟？
This means you are...
这代表你是…
The prince of North Korea?
朝鲜的王子？
you seem surprised
你好像很惊讶
Is it because she has a good appearance as rumored?
因为如传闻般有着姣好面貌吗
We woke up in the palace at that time
我们当时就是在宫中醒来的啊
I thought you already had a idea in your mind
我以为你心里已经有个底了
Why don't you speak?
你怎么不说话了？
Because I don’t know what to say either
因为我也不知道该说些什么
The words I wanted to say but disappeared
想说出口却又消失的字句
It seems to be because of the intimidating effect of the word "Maharaja"
似乎是因为「大君」二字的恫吓效果
What's wrong with you? It doesn't look like you.
你是怎么了  真不像你
I'm thinking about every word I've said so far
我正在回想至今说过的字字句句
Have I committed treason?
我是否犯了大逆之罪呢
If I commit it, will you give me a chance to atone?
若犯下了  你会给我赎罪的机会吗
Just do as you originally did
照你原本的做就好
Do you want me to continue to offend you so that I can be beheaded?
你的意思是要我继续冒犯你  好被砍头吗
are you making fun of me
你在挖苦我吗
I've never met anyone remotely related to the royal family.
我至今从未见过和王室有一丝渊源之人
However, one day the core of the royal family
然而某天王室的核心
Even when the highest person appears before me
甚至是在最高位之人出现在我面前
Aren't you going to panic?
你难道不会慌吗
That's why I didn't say anything
所以我才没说出口
Because everyone doesn’t know how to treat me after hearing this
因为大家听完都不知怎么对待我
And feel uncomfortable
而且觉得不自在
It’s not because the name “Maharaja” is so great that we hide it
并不是因为「大君」这名讳多伟大才隐瞒
It's an order from now on
现在起是命令
I order you to continue to treat me as you did before.
我命你继续像之前那样对待我
You are not allowed to disobey
不许你违抗
Because when I woke up, I was in the palace
因为醒来时身在宫中
I thought you were an official who came to the government office to report
我以为你是来官厅禀告的从事官
Who would have thought that it was your home?
谁会想到那竟是你的家
In this North Korea, are there more than fifteen people in the palace?
在这朝鲜  宫阙是自己家的人有超过十五名吗
There should be more than ten
应该有超过十个
After all, I have something to hide, so I’m not qualified to say anything.
毕竟我也有隐瞒事情  没资格说什么
But there are still difficulties now
但现在还是有困难
If you don't want to, just refuse.
不愿意就拒绝吧
Wait, your mother is starving in the palace.
等等  你母亲正在宫中挨饿
But did you actually say such unfilial words?
但你竟然说出如此不孝的话吗
After all, that body is not very filial.
毕竟那副身躯并没有多孝顺
So you want me to...
所以你要我…
Let the former mother of the country starve to death?
让曾为国母的那位大人饿死吗
It’s not that I don’t want to go, I just want you to give me an alternative.
我不是不去  是要你给出替代方案
It's going to be daybreak, hurry up
天就要亮了  要快
Just do as I say
乖乖照我的话做
First put your hands behind your back
首先把手背在背后
Keep your waist straight at all times
腰杆随时都要挺直
Look as arrogant as possible
表情尽可能傲慢
what
什么
Didn't you say he would enter the palace?
你不是说他会入宫吗
The adults are here
大人来了
It turns out that she is the concubine.
原来那位便是大妃娘娘
Don't be timid. Just do as he says.
不要畏畏缩缩的  按照他说的做就好
Anyway, the words that came out of my mouth
反正从我口中说出的话
None of it represents my opinion
都不代表我的意见
The Queen Mother is getting older
母后娘娘年岁渐增
He seems to be becoming more and more stubborn.
似乎也越来越固执了
Why not eat or drink?
为何要不吃不喝呢
Wouldn't it hurt this beautiful appearance?
岂不是伤了这美丽的容貌
Where did you spend the night the past two days?
你这两天都在哪里过夜
What a surprise
真意外
She actually had no reaction to my frivolous words
她居然对我轻浮的言语毫无反应
It’s just a place with the sky as its home and the wind as its mattress.
不过是以天为家  以风为褥的某处罢了
Are you also friends with that woman?
也以那个女人为友吗
Woman?
女人？
Well...you never mentioned women. Who is she talking about?
那个…你没提过女人啊  她是在说谁
I don't know either
我也不知道
Who else knows?
那还有谁知道
I saw it with my own eyes last night
我昨夜亲眼见到了
You hold the hand of a girl from unknown family and play in the palace
你牵着不知哪家闺女的手在宫里嬉戏
Concubine, you misunderstood
大妃娘娘你误会了
That girl has nothing to do with me
那位姑娘和我毫无关系
Yesterday was the first time we met
我们昨天是第一次见面
No, it shouldn’t be the first time
不对  应该不算第一次
Is this the second time?
算是第二次吗
Don't let me act rashly with that face
顶着那张脸不许给我冒冒失失的
Keep up the good demeanor of a great king
保持好大君的风范
Now that I've seen it
既然见到了
Tell me which family you are a daughter of
告诉我是哪个家族的闺秀
Play dumb
快装傻
I don't know. I really don't know.
我不知道  真的不知道
Do you want me to capture all the ladies in North Korea before you open your mouth?
要我把全朝鲜的闺秀抓来  你才肯开口吗
Said it was just a chance meeting and spending the night together
说只是萍水相逢共度一夜的关系
Don't know her name
不清楚她的姓名
It's just a chance meeting and spending the night together
只是萍水相逢共度一夜的关系
what
什么
Have you fallen in love like a common man?
你是谈了市井小民般的自由恋爱吗
Because they are just ordinary people in the city.
因为就是市井小民啊
what did you say
你说什么
you guy
你这家伙
I feel deeply frightened that my son has become like this.
把令郎变成如此  深感惶恐
That's not what I meant
不是这个意思
I mean, as a common citizen, I feel deeply frightened.
我是指身为市井小民  深感惶恐
As a king of a country, he cannot be a model of a gentleman.
身为一国大君竟不能成为君子的典范
What are you still doing standing there? Call the doctor quickly.
还站在那里做什么  快请御医
You are obviously not in good health, why do you go on a hunger strike to this point...
明明身体不好  为何要绝食至此…
What to do if something goes wrong
万一出问题该如何是好
Your Majesty is very worried about you.
大君大人非常担心你
I kept chattering all day long until my little one even memorized it.
整天喋喋不休到小的都背起来了
Yeah, that's it
是啊  就是如此
Are you okay?
你没什么大碍吧
take your hands away
把手拿开
bad guy
坏家伙
How could you spend one night with someone's precious daughter and then abandon her?
怎么能带着人家的宝贝闺女共度一夜就抛开
I never taught you this
我可没有这样教导过你
If you still know how to respect me
如果你还知道尊重我
At least you should show some reflection.
至少也该摆出反省的样子
I will reflect on it
我会反省的
I don’t think I’ve seen you as a palace maid before.
我好像没见过你这名宫女
Small?
小的吗
The young one has just entered the residence of the Maharaja.
小的才刚进大君大人府上
what is your name
你叫什么
Xiao Wei Hong Shi
小的为洪诗
Hong Shi?
洪诗？
What's wrong? What's the problem?
怎么了  有什么问题
Please express your condolences
请你节哀
It’s all because women who shouldn’t be in the house are like this.
都是家中进了不该进的女人才会如此
If you want a drink, come out
要喝一杯的话就出来吧
Zai Yi
载伊
No need for wine
酒就不必了
That one...
那位…
It’s Eunjo’s mother
是恩祖的母亲
I wonder if I can let her meet secretly
不知是否能偷偷让她见上一面
She said she wanted to go back to her parents' house, so I kept silent.
她说要回娘家一趟  所以我才默不作声
It's all my fault for making you disliked by the concubine.
都怪我  害你被大妃娘娘讨厌了
Don't take it to heart, it won't be a matter of a day or two anyway.
别放在心上  反正也不是一两天的事了
We can't be together all the time
我们也不能一直在一起
I will also take this body back to your husband's house before tomorrow morning.
明早前我也要带着这副身躯回你夫家一趟
You can also hide in another courtyard during the mourning period
服丧期间还能躲在别院
But there's a funeral tomorrow
但明天就要出殡了
No matter what, I have to show up.
怎么说也要露个面
can you do this for me
你能替我这样做吗
Didn’t you say you must protect me?
你不是说必须守护吗
Although I don’t know what I can protect with this marriage.
虽然我也不懂用这段婚姻能守护什么
But can you do it alone?
不过你有办法自己一个人吗
Be sure to do it
务必要做到
Protect each other's lives and find a way to get back on track.
守护好彼此的生活  找出回到正轨的方法
Then you have to stay up late with me today
那么你今天就必须和我一起熬夜
who is she
她是谁啊
Why pretend to be a palace maid?
为什么要佯装成宫女
They have been in the room for three hours. What on earth are they doing?
他们在房里已三个时辰  究竟在做什么？
That's right. Your Majesty has an order.
就是啊　　大君大人有令
Any information leaked to outsiders will be severely punished
若是向外泄漏任何讯息一律严惩
The character illustrations around you should look like this.
你身边的人物图鉴差不多这样就行了
The rest depends on my superb adaptability.
剩下就靠我高超的应变能力来处理
There's something about that...
那个有件事…
Is there anything else you want to explain?
还有什么要交代的吗
It's been hard for me to open my mouth to you during this time.
这段时间我一直不好向你开口
what
什么
our each other's bodies
我们彼此的身体
Just pretend you can't see it
就请你当作看不见吧
Ah
啊
Now is the time to draw the line
现在才来划清界线
You've finished watching everything you should see, right?
该看的都已经看完了吧
No, I didn't see anything.
才没有  我什么都没看到
This is not what I saw
这不是我看的
It’s seen by the person in front of me, so it’s you who sees it
是由我眼前的人来看  所以是你看的
Sounds like I looked at it carefully once
听起来像是仔细看过一次了
And my body too
还有我的身体也是
It was not you who touched it, but my own hand.
不是你来碰触  而是由我自己的手碰触的
You got it
你明白了吧
Is that so?
是这样吗
But I am the one who has the memory
不过有记忆的人是我
Sir, don’t you also know?
大人　　你不是也知道
I'm very confident
我很有自信的
I haven't seen it
我没看过
I said it wasn't with my eyes
我说过那不是由我眼睛看的
Go ask Dazao to come
去叫大枣来吧
what does it mean
什么意思
Are you avoiding my question?
你是在回避我的问题吗
I start walking back from here
我从这里开始走路回去
Someone might see it accidentally
不小心可能会有人看到
Good
好
jujube
大枣
No, Judge Xu
不对  徐判官
Please follow the Lord at all times
请你时时刻刻跟随在主君身边
Notice if he is trembling with fear
注意他是否被吓到发抖
Is the behavior reckless?
举止是否冒冒失失
Did you eat on time?
有没有按时吃饭
Or whether you are alone at night...
或是夜里是否独自…
cry secretly
偷偷哭泣
Please pay close attention to
麻烦你好好留意
No need to remind you
不劳你提醒
This is my duty
这是我的分内之事
Just know
知道就好
Although other people's emotional affairs...
虽然他人的感情之事…
should not interfere excessively
不应过度干涉
But if you dare to use the Maharaja
但如果你敢利用大君大人
Or let him get hurt
或是让他受到伤害
I will definitely take action myself by then
届时我肯定会亲自出手
Have you been acting cool in private?
你一直私下耍帅吗
what
什么
I was almost fascinated by you
我差点被你迷住了
wait a moment
等一下
everyone stop thinking
大家停止思考
Mother
娘
young master
少爷
Why did you come here?
你们怎么会过来
Where did you go, girl?
你这丫头跑去哪里了
The young master talks without thinking
少爷说话不经大脑
Even if he talks nonsense, don't pay attention to it.
就算他胡说八道也别理会
He is very kind and not a bad person
他很善良  人不坏
Do you wish you were left out?
你是不是巴不得被冷落
How do you know my wish
你怎么知道我的愿望
what
什么
Master, it will be good if she comes back safely
少爷  她平安回来就好了
The patient I was caring for was not feeling well, so I went to visit him.
我照顾的患者不舒服  我去探望
Thank you for taking so much trouble.
竟然如此费心  辛苦你了
You're just so nosy anyway
反正你就是这么爱多管闲事
Do you still want to be a medical woman now?
事到如今还想当医女？
The person who has passed away has passed away
逝去之人已逝
Those who are alive must live on
活着的人总要活下去
I see you are not sad at all
我看你一点也不伤心
It's like waiting for the eldest father of this family to pass away
就像在等待这个家的大老爷过世
Mother, look
娘  快看
This girl doesn't answer
这丫头不回答
I understand
我明白了
The reason why you concealed your husband's identity was that you insisted on getting married.
你之所以隐瞒丈夫身分  硬是成亲
It's all for a reason
都是有原因的
You already knew he would pass away
你早就知道他会过世了
No wonder you must marry even if your mother objects.
难怪即使娘反对  你也一定要嫁人
Did I even hide this from my family?
我居然连家人都瞒着吗
Still want to escape?
还想逃避？
Actually, you want to act like a lady from another hall, right?
其实你是想摆出别堂夫人的架势吧
Yes, whatever you say
对  随便你怎么说
Mother, let’s go
娘  走吧
We worry about her for nothing
我们白替她担心了
chat with me
和我聊聊
She is someone who only worries about me and my family.
她是一心只担心我和家人的人
So I insisted on getting married against my mother’s wishes?
所以我违背娘的意思  执意出嫁？
Once you make up your mind, you will definitely do it
你一旦下定决心就一定会做到
No one can stop you, so I didn’t try to hold you back.
谁都拦不住你  所以我也没多加挽留
I understand too
我也明白
You raised your daughter to be very stubborn
你把女儿教得很固执
in retrospect
回想起来
Maybe that's why I didn't stop you
或许我是以此为由  才没有拦你
As a mother, I am really shameless.
我这个做娘的真是没面子
I'm asking this because I really don't understand.
我是真的不明白才会这样问
Mother’s daughter…
娘的女儿…
How should I feel now?
现在应该要是什么心情呢
poor child
可怜的孩子
Of course you won't know
你当然不会知道
Because it's all buried
因为都埋藏起来了
Buried in the words "It doesn't matter"
埋在「没关系」这句话中
Your Majesty
大君大人
It has been confirmed that she has entered the house
已经确认她进屋了
Thank you for your hard work. Go and rest.
辛苦了  去休息吧
That…
那个…
When I followed your whereabouts, I discovered something
我追踪你的行迹时  发现了一件事
Do you know that woman?
请问你知道那位女子
Marrying someone?
与谁成亲吗
In the end, it was discovered
结果还是被发现了
What a surprise
真是出乎意料
I was hoping at least he wouldn't know
我原本希望至少他别知情
Your Majesty, are you okay?
大君大人  你没事吧
It's okay
没事
It must be okay
必须没事才行
Does it mean I always put myself last?
意思是  我总是将自己排在最后吗
it's all my fault
都是我的错
I only teach you to be patient and hold on.
我只教你要忍耐  要撑下去
Sorry Eunjo
对不起  恩祖
It seems that this body should be protected the most.
看来这副身体最该守护的人
It's my mother, right?
是娘吧
No, don't do that
不  别那样做
Take it
收下吧
This is the money I borrowed from the Consul of the Art Museum.
这是和艺文馆领事大人借的钱
Why did you give me this money?
为何给我这笔钱
Although like you said
虽然就像你说的
After becoming the concubine of a powerful man, I don’t have to worry about food and clothing.
当了权贵的小妾后不愁吃穿
I don’t have to worry about money and my life is very stable.
也不愁钱  日子很安稳
Dan Enzu
但恩祖
Even if life is good
即使过得好
Even if life is really good
即使真的过得很好
If one day you feel regret and want to run away
若有天你感到后悔  想逃跑
Just take this money and go
就带着这笔钱走吧
I heard that as long as you escape to the Ming Dynasty, no one will catch you.
听说只要逃到明国  就没人抓得到
Leave me and the Superintendent alone
别管我和大监大人
Go far away
走得远远的吧
Promise your mother about this, okay?
答应娘这件事  好吗
If it were the original well-behaved daughter
若是原本那个乖巧的女儿
I will definitely agree
肯定会答应的
But now I have to make another promise
但现在的我要许下另一个约定
what is
是什么
I won't let a drop of water get on your hands
我不会让你的手沾上任何一滴水
How did that go?
那件事进展如何
We used the name of the thief Ji Tong
我们用了盗贼吉童之名
Ji Tong?
吉童？
They are the thieves who robbed Da Si Jian's warehouse.
就是洗劫大司谏库房的盗贼
Da Sijian also mentioned that person before he passed away
大司谏过世前也提过那个人
I hate that thief so much
对那盗贼极其厌恶
No one should doubt
应该不会有人怀疑
black sword
黑剑
What's going on in the Robbery Hall?
捕盗厅有什么动静
They are searching for the whereabouts of people around Da Si Jian
他们正在搜查大司谏身旁人士的行踪
Don't leave this to anyone else
这件事别交给其他人
Watch it yourself
你亲自盯着
Yes
是
Is this North Korea what you got?
你得到的是这个朝鲜吗
you guy
你这家伙
Aren't you afraid of divine punishment?
都不怕天谴吗
If the Lord knows
若主上知道了
You will definitely be punished by the three tribes
你肯定会被诛三族
punished with lingchi
处以凌迟之刑
If you want to live
若是想活
Give me half of the country of Korea
就分一半的朝鲜江山给我
The so-called greed...
所谓贪欲…
When a fool becomes greedy, he is seeking his own death.
当愚者起了贪念  便是自寻死路
Remember to engrave this lesson on your rotting flesh
记得将此教训刻在你将腐烂的肉身上
You may meet other royal families during the day
白天可能会遇见其他王族
While everyone is asleep
趁着大家熟睡时
Memorize the location of the palace
将宫阙的位置记熟
Zhang Shurong
张淑容
She is Jinlu who has only heard rumors
她便是只听过传闻的金绿
It's medicinal
是药材味
Where did it come from?
从哪里传来的
First time I smell this smell
初次闻到这种味道
Although inhaling smoke from burning medicinal herbs can alleviate symptoms
虽然吸入燃烧药材的烟能减缓症状
If there is so much smoke that it spreads outside the house, it will be dangerous.
若是烟雾多到弥漫至屋外是会有危险的
Who would treat this way?
谁会用这种方式治疗
Kangnyeongjeon
康宁殿
His Royal Highness's sleeping quarters
殿下的寝殿
No matter what happens, I cannot see His Highness.
不论遇到什么事  都不能见到殿下
No
不行
There's a time and a place to meddle in other people's business, right?
多管闲事也要分时间与地点不是吗
Your Majesty?
大君大人？
Can't let others know I've been here
不能让别人知道我来过这里
Yes
是
The treatment going on in the dormitory...
寝殿内正在进行的治疗…
It’s so noisy…
吵死了…
The little one is deeply frightened, Your Highness.
小的深感惶恐  殿下
Are you suffering from sores?
受疮疾所苦吗
Yes
是
What's the matter
有什么事
Please be quiet
拜托安静
What should I do if I wake up His Highness later?
等一下把殿下吵醒了怎么办
Palace…
殿…
Next?
下？
Do you want to confirm the medicinal materials?
你想确认药材？
Yes, Your Highness
是的  殿下
The little one goes out for a walk
小的出来散步
Your Highness, the smoke must be dispersed outside the house first.
殿下  必须先将烟雾散到屋外
You guys come here to help. We need to ventilate it first.
你们过来帮忙  要先通风
You guys move faster
你们动作快点
what are you doing
你这是在做什么
Your Highness, no matter what kind of treatment
殿下  不管何种治疗
Excessive use will cause side effects
只要过度都会产生副作用
Do you want to refute the doctor's prescription?
你想反驳御医的处方吗
Of course I don't dare
我当然不敢
But according to my experience
不过根据我的经验
For sores, you must drink water boiled from bezoar and honeysuckle.
疮疾必须饮用牛黄、金银花所熬之水
Apply ointment and ventilate frequently to facilitate recovery
擦药膏  并常通风才利于痊愈
I hope you don't rely on new medicinal materials
希望你别依赖新的药材
Existing treatments must be tried simultaneously
必须同步尝试既有的疗法
It seems you know my symptoms very well
看来你很清楚我的症状
That makes you look so disappointed
才会看起来如此失望
Because it’s not a terminal illness
因为并非绝症
what
什么
That's not what I meant by being small
小的并非此意
Just in the smoke
只不过是在烟雾弥漫中
Seeing you in pain
看见你痛苦不已
what did you say
你说什么
Although the sore wound is not big, it is easy to ignore it
虽说疮疾伤口不大  容易轻忽
However, it is easy for patients to have such minor injuries affect their daily lives.
不过患者容易因为这种小伤影响日常
Over time, it will affect your life
时间久了  进而影响生活
As a result, patients suffering from disease
如此一来  身受疾病所苦的患者
My heart will gradually become sick
心中也会逐渐生病
I just want to lighten some of your burdens
小的只不过是想替你减轻一些负担
That's out of proportion. You're meddling in other people's business.
才有失分寸  多管闲事了
It sounded so sincere that I almost choked up.
听起来真心诚意  害我差点哽咽了呢
Back off
退下吧
Yes, Your Highness
是的  殿下
I actually saw His Highness the Lord
居然见到主上殿下了
Is his relationship with the Maharaja not good?
他与大君的关系不好吗
Let's go back to the dormitory
还是回寝殿吧
The time has come for people to decide...
已到人定之时…
I was so flustered that I didn’t even think about Ji Dong’s side.
太过慌乱  完全没想到吉童那边
Have you caught the real culprit?
抓到真凶了吗
Still in the period of confinement and unable to leave the palace
尚在禁足期间  又不能出宫
What to do
该如何是好
Are you saying it's not Ji Tong?
你说不是吉童吗
Isn’t it written in the blood book?
血书上不是写了吗
We're investigating people who have a grudge against sinners
我们正在调查对罪人心怀怨恨之人
Do you think my adults are sinners?
你说我家大人是罪人吗
It would be unjust enough just to die.
只是死去就够冤枉了
He actually regarded him as a sinner
居然还把他视为罪人
You bad guys
你们这班坏蛋
You send her home
你送她回家
Yes
是
let me go
给我放手
Ji Tong?
吉童？
catch up
追上去
Ji Dong, this damn guy
吉童这该死的家伙
No shooting allowed, must be captured alive
不许射杀  必须活捉
Sir
大人
Report this matter to your Majesty immediately
立刻向大君大人禀报此事
obey
遵命
I actually got a glimpse of North Korea's most traitorous official
我竟能窥见朝鲜头号奸臣
Du Chengzhi Ren Shiheng’s family secrets
都承旨任士衡的门第的家门秘事
Zhang Shurong?
张淑容？
Why are you here dressed like this?
你怎么会穿成这样来这里
Lord Daoyue seems to know the truth about the medicinal materials
道月大君似乎知道药材的真相了
Lord Daoyue?
道月大君吗
yes
是的
He took away all the incense
他把香全撤掉了
What's going on
怎么回事
How could they mention my banned account?
他们口中怎会提及我的封号呢
Ji Tong was arrested
吉童被拘捕了
Oops, lucky boy... lucky boy?
哎呀  吉童…　　吉童吗
I heard he was caught by the Robbery Hall
听说他被捕盗厅抓住了
What should people do?
这让人怎么办才好
Enzu
恩祖
are you from the cemetery
你是从墓地来的吗
Are you feeling well?
你身体还好吗
much better
好多了
But what does it mean that Ji Dong was arrested?
不过吉童被拘捕是什么意思
I just heard about it too
我也是刚刚才听说
I heard that Ji Tong was hit by an arrow yesterday.
听说昨天吉童中箭了
what
什么
Enzu
恩祖
Did the Lord disappear out of thin air again?
大人竟又凭空失踪了吗
Seeing that there was no movement inside, I went in to take a look.
见里面毫无动静  这才进去一看
But found that the person was no longer there
却发现人早已不在
The case is settled
此案就此了结
Yes
是
Wait
等等
Doctor Hong
洪医女
Is this person Ji Dong?
这个人就是吉童吗
The adults folded the bedding and night clothes so neatly?
大人竟将被褥和夜装折得如此整齐？
Not only that
不只如此
The adults even cleaned
大人甚至还打扫了
Something is wrong
大事不妙了
Go to the Maharaja immediately
立刻去找大君大人
What happened?
发生什么事了吗
scared me
吓我一跳
Sir, where have you run to?
大人你跑去哪里了
In the inner hospital, I went to boil the medicine and deliver it to the concubine’s palace.
内医院  我去煎药送到大妃殿的汤药
what
什么
I feel like this is the only way to alleviate the guilt in my heart
觉得只有如此  才能稍减心中的愧疚
Then why fold the bedding and night clothes?
那为什么要折被褥和夜装
Easy to fold when you wake up
起床顺手折的
Why didn't you tell us?
怎么不吩咐我们呢
Did you put on the clothes yourself?
衣冠也是你亲自穿上的吗
Yes, I want you to sleep more
对  想让你们多睡一点
if we make any mistakes
如果我们犯了什么错
please tell us directly lord
请直接告诉我们  大人
What's wrong
什么错啊
Send the doctor in immediately. Immediately.
立刻传医员进来  马上
What's going on with you guys?
你们到底是怎么回事
Your Majesty
大君大人
Officer Park from the Robbery Bureau asked for an audience.
捕盗厅的朴军官求见
Has the news gotten out?
消息已经传出去了吗
Ji Tong died on the spot after being hit by an arrow
吉童中箭后当场死亡
Ji Tong is dead?
吉童死了？
Where is the fake lucky boy?
假吉童呢
Disposed of
处理掉了
Clean it up yourself
你亲自收拾干净
obey
遵命
Buried
埋好了
Have a good trip, Ji Tong
一路好走  吉童
Let's go Yes
走吧　　是
Maybe the real murderer will come and take away the body of the fake Ji Tong
说不定真凶会来将假吉童的尸身收走
Still collected neatly
还收得整整齐齐
This is…
这是…
Do I really have that?
我真的有那样吗
Are they really collected neatly?
真的收得整整齐齐吗
I really can't stand it
真是受不了
So what should I do?
那我到底该怎样做才好
Is it because I don’t know how to read people’s emotions? Did I come in too early?
是我不会察言观色  太早进来了吗
From now on, count to ten at the door before coming in.
以后在门口数到十再进来
The way you look at me
你看我的眼神
Shaking very violently
晃动得很剧烈
what do you want
你想怎样
I want you not to do anything
要你什么事都别做的意思
Your majesty keeps getting in my way for some reason
大君就不知为何一直在妨碍我
Your Majesty's maid, please stay.
大君大人的宫女  请留步